Tyler Minegar

Senior Software Engineer

About Me

Full Stack Developer with 8+ years of experience on modern Frontend and Backend Web Developements.

Consulting basic business models, realized pixel-pefect design, implemented scalable & maintainable components with clear requirements.

Highly experienced, solutions-oriented professional in overseeing all aspects of the SDLC from extensive analysis and design through deployments and maintenance, Agile environment, DevOps and Team collaboration.

Creative, Result-Focused, Passionate & Self-Learner. Keep Curious and ahead about new technologies.

☑ Email tyler.minegar01@gmail.com⑤ Skype live:.cid.d6b53bd69d7055a0

→ Phone +1 520 720 0990

Telegram @tylerminegar

Address 907, Huff Ave, Manvile, NJ, 08835,

USA

Professional Skills React NodeJS MASTER VUEJS PHP EXPERT Angular Python ADVANCE MASTER Java

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer at Telmie

Oct, 2021 - Present

Telmie is an online marketplace for professional services in real-time, makes it easy for anyone to find and talk to an expert who can help them to achieve their goal.

- As a fullstack developer, I started with website design and developed a website with MERN stack.
- Worked in a Test-Driven-Development and Agile environment like Scrum and Kanban Methodologies.
- Here we use the JS framework React JS and build a flexible and modern frontend with powerful ideas.
- Built Testing cases using Jest and cypress and covered coverage by 90%.
- Developed backend and database model and schema with Node.js, MongoDB and MySQL
- Wrote GraphQL queries on existing database and integrated GraphQL APIs to the frontend.
- Deployed serverless applications using AWS lambda and worked with AWS S3 and DynamoDB.

O Senior Frontend Engineer at Lighthouse

Nov, 2019 - Sep, 2021

Lighthouse is a timber-framed modular manufacturer and offer both bespoke and standardised homes, build houses, apartments and bungalows (and occasionally bird observatories).

- Implemented User Friendly Interface by using React 16 / TS & Styled components and built frontend side of several applications and React and also built educational platform using React / TS / MUI
- Implemented Redux data structure and making APIs calls with Redux-Thunk.
- Mainly developed JS/TS based projects using React and Vue for the frontend side.
- I also worked with backend engineers to enhance security and manage on-site assessments, internal audits and customer surveys.
- Slack and Jira for team communication and management.

• Frotend Developer at Skillr

May, 2017 - Oct, 2019

Skillr's making the world's knowledge and entertainment more accessible than ever, enable anyone to video chat one-on-one live with an expert instantly and seamlessly.

- Implemented frontend solutions for web applications using modern JS frameworks (React, Next.js).
- Collaborated with the team to design new features and enhancements of existing system.
- Created reusable components that can be used across multiple projects as well as optimized code for performance in large scale applications.
- Participated in architectural review meetings regarding application development practices and participated in technical discussions about implementation details of various features or fixes.

Education

2013 - 2017

Bachelor's degree of Computer and Information Engineering from University of Southern California